The name in my vehicle policy is wrong.
Some digits in my address are wrong
or my address has just been updated.
My vehicle was petrol but
diesel has been mentioned in the policy. So can
your claim be rejected because of these details?
How should you get these details corrected
and will you have to pay extra money to get them corrected? If
you too have faced any of these problems, then do let
me know by commenting in the comment area
and let's start the video.
I will tell you
how to get each detail corrected one by one and whether
you will have to pay any charge for it or not. The first
detail is brother, registration number. This is the number
which is written on the number plate of the vehicle
and this is its identity proof. Like
what is our identity proof, our Aadhar
card, Aadhar number. If there is a
mistake in your registration number, will the claim be
rejected? It will definitely happen
because if you enter incorrect details
in the insurance policy, then the
insurance company will immediately reject the claim here.
So can it be corrected? It can
definitely be done. You will have to pay
extra money. The
insurance company will not do this.  They do
not charge any extra money for such collection,
so how to get it rectified? First of all, I would
advise you that if you are in
touch with the person from whom you have purchased the insurance, then
first of all, give this to them because it is
their mistake. You have purchased your insurance from them and
you are taking the service from them, then you can
ask them to get it rectified, but
many times nowadays we buy insurance online
or that IT or
consultant is not in our touch, then
you can get it rectified easily,
you have to write a small email to the insurance company, you will get
their customer care address email
ID online, you have to search the
name of your insurance company and
its care email ID, you have to
send an email to that email ID, in the subject you have to
write Update Registration Number on
RC and in the message you have to write that
this is my vehicle number and this is the policy number
which I have purchased from your company and the
registration number in it is wrong, it should be rectified according to the RC,
you will also see a sample format on the screen,
you can take a screenshot of it and along with it
you have to attach the documents, one is the
RC of the vehicle and the insurance policy  After doing this,
you send the email and
after some time you will
get the policy copy along with the collection and there will be no
problem in your claim as well.
Now as I mentioned above, no
insurance company will
charge you any fee for making this change but it is
possible that some consultant or insurance agent may take
money from you, it may be his convenience or
service charge but the
insurance company does not charge such fees. The
second detail is friends, the name of the owner
i.e. the name in the RC, if there is a spelling
mistake in the caste, there is a mistake in the surname
or in the salutation,
instead of Mr., does it cause any
problem in the claim? It is definitely true, it is true
brother, your name should be exactly the same in the RC and the policy. The
same thing happened with my friend, he bought an old car to sell
and whatever was supposed to be in the RC was the same as
before, the old
owner was the same and he
bought the insurance policy in his name. Now
when I noticed this thing, I said that
brother, the insurance policy is in someone else's name and the
RC is in someone else's name.  How is this possible, then he
said that brother the car is in his name, I am
doing it for him, so I have taken the insurance policy of my
childhood in my name, you do not have to do it
this way, you will not get the claim in this way, the
details which are in the RC should be there
in the policy only because he is the valid owner
and he will get the claim, so if there is a mistake in the spelling of your name, surname
or celebration, then
you can get it corrected,
I told you how to get the customer care email ID,
after that you have to write
update name on RC and in the subject matter of the
message you have to write that my name is
this in the RC, then please correct the RCS details in my policy as well
and
along with that the document which you have to attach is the
RC insurance policy of the vehicle and
because this is related to your name,
you will also have to attach your PAN card and Aadhar
card which is your identity proof
in it and email it
to the insurance company, this option will be available to you easily
and for this also the insurance company will
not charge you anything, now
after the name there is a big number of address, friends if
your address  The P-code is incorrect,
or your address is correct but has now been
updated. You've moved, so
your address has changed.
How can you correct it? If your address is incorrect, you
can easily get it corrected by email. You won't face any problems.
If your address has changed, you should
enter it in your communication address.
Since January 1, 2013, the address proof in your KYC will be included
in your policy.
First, your KYC will be verified,
and the address listed in that proof will be included in
your policy. However,
if you've moved and moved, you
can enter your address in your communication address.
What's the benefit of using a communication address? If the address is
incorrect,
the company may want to send you a notice or a
letter that
won't be delivered to the correct address.
If they require any information, they
won't be able to provide it.
This could delay or reject your claim. So,
always keep your address.
Keep it correct so that any information the
insurance company wants to send to you
reaches you directly. If your
address is wrong, you can get it corrected through email.
And
in many of the applications of insurance companies, now there is an
option to update your address directly,
update your mobile number, email ID
directly without paying any charges. The
next common mistake is related to fuel, i.e. if a
petrol vehicle is written as diesel or a diesel
vehicle is mentioned as petrol, then you should get this kind
of mistake corrected as well.
What is the reason? The
discounting on this, which is the pricing of your policy, is done by the
insurance company.
Along with this, petrol vehicles are cheaper and
diesel vehicles are expensive, so on this
basis, the ID of your vehicle i.e. the
value is also included in the insurance. So
if your fuel type is wrong, then you may face
problems in the claim as well. You should get it
corrected
through correction only. This will be done easily.
You will not have to pay any extra money for this.
What will you get in the email for this collection?  You have to
write in the subject line, update my
fuel type, in the RC message you have to
write that this is my registration number,
this is the policy number and the fuel type of my
vehicle is wrong, it should be
updated on the RC and the
documents that you have to attach are your RC
and insurance policy. Now it is possible that the
ID of your model may also increase, that is, the
value of the vehicle may increase or its
ID may also decrease or decrease, then according to that there
may be some fluctuation in the price, the insurance company will
not charge you for making this change, but if
some additional value is added to your policy
and for that your premium increases
or some discounting is reduced, there is any
difference in the price, then
you may have to pay that money. Now this is about
petrol and diesel, if you have
added CNG to your vehicle, then
how do you get it updated? See, there
is a totally different procedure for that. I have
told you a simple method in this that there has been a manual error, there has been a
writing mistake, but otherwise nothing
new has been added to your vehicle  If yes, then you
can get it done directly through email,
but if you have got it
added then its process is totally
different,
it will be inspection of your vehicle, the
invoice value of CNG will be
added to your policy, extra money will be
charged from you for that, so it is a very long
process, so in this I would advise you to get this
CNG endorsement done from an insurance agent or consultant,
but if it is typical for petrol and
diesel to be switched by mistake, then
you can get it done directly through email also, there are a lot of
digits in these, if
you look at the numbers then
you will find 14-15 digits, if any digit is missing or
wrong, if it is ahead or behind then
you may have to
face claim rejection due to that detail, so
you must get it corrected, it is a normal process,
you have to write the same email, in the subject you have to write
update my angel or chas number whichever
is wrong, on RC, in the message you have to write that
this is my vehicle number, policy number and
it should be updated according to RC,
along with RC and insurance policy will be
attached to you  Now these problems do
not cause any problem in small claims, for example, if a
claim of Rs 5-10 is made then
no insurance company is going to bother you,
but if there is a major claim, for example, if the
total claim is Rs 5 lakh or Rs 10 lakh, then the insurance
company does more investigation,
they just want a small
point and we reject the claim, so to
avoid this, keep the engine and chassis number
correct, you must check once that
it matches with your RC,
if it is not correct then get it corrected, and
see, I told you that in most of the
changes, you do
not have to pay any extra money, you just have to get it corrected,
see, this is your responsibility,
now friends, getting a loan on a car is a very
common thing, but many times we
forget the name of the bank which is mentioned in the RC,
if this bank's name is not mentioned in your policy then the
company will not settle the claim,
but your claim will get delayed
because your loss will increase
Your documentation will be ruined. If there is a small repair
claim, then there is no use of the bank there.
Suppose you have a
repair claim of Rs. 50,000, the
insurance company will settle your claim directly. The
bank has nothing to do with it.
But when has the problem arisen? When a big claim
amount is made, if it is a total loss, the
car is stolen, the car is damaged, in
which the insurance company will pay you the claim amount of the full value of the car. There is a problem in that.
What will happen?
Your claim will get delayed because in that the
insurance company will first clear the outstanding amount of the bank and
then will
give you the remaining amount. But if the
name of the bank is not updated in your policy and the name of the bank is there in the RC, then
this can be a complication.
Therefore, according to your RC, get your
bank's hypothecation, hire purchase, mentioned
in your policy. And if
your loan is cleared but still
your RCM bank's name is there, then get it
cleared. It is not that the insurance
company will still pay the money to the bank, but later
your claim will be delayed.  There may be a delay in your
formalities. You have to
read the
name of the bank from the RC if the loan
is clear and if the RCM is the bank's name then
mention it in your policy. If it is yet to be mentioned then
you can get it updated through email also.
You have to write "Update Hypothecation or Hire Purchase RC" in the subject
and write in the email message
that I have a loan on my vehicle from this bank. The
hypothecation as per my RC should be
updated in my policy. It will be
updated. You will not have to pay any charge for this also. The
next common mistake is
friends, suppose the model or variant of the vehicle is
my base model and I have
mentioned the top model in the policy, will the
insurance company give me the claim? It will not give it
because there is a difference of ₹300000 between the base model and the top model
and my vehicle is the base
model, so how can I claim that amount?
We have to get it rectified. There is a
process for getting it rectified. You have to send an email
in the subject of the email you have to
write "Update my model variant is RC".  You have to
write in the message that this model of mine has gone
wrong, the RC recording of
this model should be updated and
in the document you have to attach the RC and insurance policy and
send it by email. The insurance company will
not have to pay any extra charge for this. However, if your model is repaired then the
value of your vehicle may be more or less because the
insurance company declares the ID of each variant separately.
So if your model
was earlier of a higher price and then it goes up, then it is
possible that its ID may also
decrease along with it. And if your earlier model
was of a lower price and then it goes up, then it is possible that
its ID may also increase. So, definitely
keep this in mind that the ID may change. However, the
insurance company will not charge you anything for making this change. Friends,
I have discussed all the main mistakes that may be there in your policy here.
I have also told you what is the solution for them
and
whether you will have to pay any money,
I have also told you this in this video. If
apart from this there is something that has gone
wrong in your policy and I have not been able to mention it in this video
So you
can ask me in the comment section, I will
answer it immediately. Now friends,
see the information in the video. If you liked it, then
immediately like the video
and do not forget to subscribe to the channel
because I, Harvinder Singh, will always
bring such interesting and informative videos for you.
Now give me your permission, I will meet you
in the next video. Till then,
take care of yourself, stay happy and stay healthy. Jai
Hind
[Music]